Mutasem Alhariri

Hilliard, Ohio | (614) 615-9307

Personal Website

malhariri992@gmail.com

| | linkedin.com/in/malhariri/

Professional Summary

A computer science student with an in-depth understanding of the software development life cycle and the object-oriented design. Analytical and creative problem solver with a strong ability to quickly learn and master new technologies. Experienced with Java, Python, Html, CSS, and SQL with hands-on experience writing, testing, debugging, and documenting programs using various software tools.

Technical Skills

Technical Skins	
Programming Languages Java JavaScript/jQuery HTML & CSS SQL Python	Tools IntelliJ Eclipse SQL Server Management Studio Visual Studio IDE PyCharm
Education & Certifications	
Franklin University, Columbus, Ohio Bachelor of Science, Computer Science	Anticipated 5/2023 GPA: 4.00

Awards/Honors: President List

AWS & Udacity Machine Learning Scholarship Recipient

06/2021-10/2021

Columbus State Community College, Columbus, Ohio Computer Science, Associate of Applied Science Degree, Software Development

8/2020 GPA: 3.81

Awards/Honors: Magna Cum Laude, Dean's List all semesters.

Relevant Experience

Capstone Project, Stellar Shoes 05/2020 to 08-2020

Columbus State Community College -Columbus, Ohio

- Collaborated with five students to create a complete IT solution
- Developed a dynamic web application in Java utilizing the Java Server Faces and Prime Faces frameworks
- Responsible for writing, debugging, testing, and documenting code, and preparing training documents
- Integrated the PayPal SDK for JavaScript as an additional payment option
- Deployed the application to AWS Elastic Beanstalk and Heroku platform
- Presented the project to instructors and faculty

Additional Projects

- Developed the backend for an inventory management system in Java using various data structures and design patterns
- Collaborated with a team of three to create a mini-web server in Java
- Utilized HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create an interactive game in a web page
- Utilized Windows Forms, ADO.NET, and SQL to build a Movies Manager desktop application
- Developed a recursive-decent parser to evaluate arithmetic expression utilizing the C programming language

Work History

Limited Brands Warehouse Associate 08/2020- 01/2021